Go, go!
走，快走
Approaching.
靠近目標
I think we have touchdown.
我想這回應該是個真傢伙
Little to the right
- 往右一點    - 好的，向右
Hello mum
你好啊，老媽
Now, push it in
好了，往裡面捅
I can't
不行啊
What do you mean you can't? Pretend it's your dick, man.
不行個屁 就把它當成你的老二，往前推
How about I pretend it's your dick?
不如我把它當成是你的老二
You'll never get in if you did that.
那你就別想完事了
- Here, let me have a shot.    - Give me a second,
- 我來試試    - 再等一會兒
- No, come on    - My dick, man    - Go
- 少來，讓開    - 這是我的老二    - 給你
Fucker
操性
- Got that    - Yeah
- 拿住了    - 嗯
Here we go
開場了
- Oh, look at that     - Nice 155, huh?     - Yeah
- 好傢伙     - 好正的T155啊     - 是啊
It's going to do some fucking damage.
這玩意兒要是炸了，可了不得
Hey, Eldridge, looks like we're going to need a charge!
喂，艾綴奇，看來需要來一次引爆
I got that.
收到
Figured four blocks that'll give us about 20 pounds of bang total.
我估計用四盒就能產生20磅當量了
That blast is going to roast straight out there.
爆炸波會一直衝到那兒
The shell will probably kick out there, and most of the shrapnel
彈殼可能會飛到那個地方
is going to shoot straight up in a beautiful umbrella pattern.
其他零散的彈片會像天女散花一樣
Yep
沒錯
We're gonna get some smaller pieces and shell fragments this way,
還有些碎彈片會飛向我們這邊
but we'll be okay if we're behind the Humvee,
只要站在軍用悍馬後面應該沒啥問題
- Bring the bot back, we'll load it up.    - No problem.
- 把機器人叫回來，準備引爆    - 好的
Bot is moving.
機器人正在返回
Let me know what you got, Eldridge.
艾綴奇，報告情況
Good to go.
已經準備好了
All right, wagon's set up. Bot moves.
好，讓小車上路
Uh-oh, we got goats, guys!
啊哦，半路殺出一幫山羊
Goats 12:00, Watch out,
注意，12點鐘方向出現羊群
Load them little bastards up.
彈藥上膛…
- Oh, shit,    - Shit,
- 哦，該死    - 該死
Oh, fuck!
他娘的
Wagon's having a bad day, boys.
小車倒了怎麼推喲
- You build that?    - No, the U.S. Army did,
- 是你造的？    - 不，是美國陸軍造的
All right, looks like I'm going down there
好，看來得我去搞定
You don't like waiting around this beautiful neighborhood?
這麼美麗的小區，不想再流連一會兒？
Oh, I love it.
哦，真喜歡這兒啊
So, if everything looks okay, when I get down there
如果一切順利，我過去之後
I'm just going to set it up and bip it,
把那玩意兒設好，然後引爆
Give these people something to think about,
讓這些傢伙明白明白
Want them to know if they're gonna leave a bomb on the side of the road for us,
既然要在我們前進的路上放炸彈
we're just going to blow up their little fuckin' road,
我們只好把他們的路炸開
Sounds good
有理
Craving a burger; is that strange?
我想吃漢堡了，是不是有些怪？
- Not for you    - No, okay
- 你這麼說，不覺得奇怪    - 那好
Helmet on
戴上頭盔
Happy trails
祝旅途愉快
Blaster One, can you read me?
我是拆彈1號，能聽見麼
Roger that, Blaster one. You're good to go.
收到，拆彈1號，你可以出發了
You're looking good, Blaster One.
拆彈1號，你看上去很棒
Nice and hot in here.
好是好，就是熱
Roger that, 150 meters
收到，150米
Hi!
喂
- Where are you from?    - Whoa, whoa, whoa!
- 你們從哪兒來？    - 且慢
Where are you from? Where are you from?    - Stop!
- 你們從哪兒來？從哪兒來的？    - 停下
California?
加利福尼亞？
- Hey, get out of here, man    - Where?
- 走開，夥計    - 是哪兒呢？
Hey, this ain't no fuckin' meet and greet. Now get out of here.
沒功夫和你閒聊，快走開！
Now
快點
Go!
走開
You making friends again, Sanborn?
又認識新朋友啦，桑伯恩？
All day long
整天都在認識
Twenty-five meters, Roger that You are now in the kill zone.
25米，收到，你已進入死亡區域
Thanks for reminding me.
謝謝提醒
That's what I'm here for, baby.
我就是幹這個的
Okay.
好吧
The debts look good.
引爆裝置沒壞
Roger that.
收到
I'm laying on the charge.
現在放引爆器
Nice and sweet.
小心輕放
We're good to go.
一切就緒
I'm coming back.
現在返回
- Five meters out.    - Five meters, Roger that.
- 已經走出5米    - 5米，收到
Hey, Sanborn
桑伯恩
- You know what this place needs?    - I'm listening.
- 知道這兒缺什麼嘛    - 說說看
Needs grass
缺草皮
We gonna start our grass business?
我們該在這兒賣草皮？
That's right, man.
沒錯，夥計
I'm going to sell the grass, you're going to cut it.
我來賣草皮，你去修草坪
It's going to be called ''Sanborn and Sons'',
公司名就叫「桑伯恩子弟」
We'll be rich.
我們會發財的
I like that, crabgrass, St. Augustine, man.
這點子我喜歡 馬唐(雜草名)，鈍葉草…
I'm a scholar on this shit,
這方面我是行家
How about this? You sell it, I fertilize it.
不如這樣，你賣草，我種草
- 25    - 25 meters, Roger that
- 25    - 25米，收到
Sanborn!
桑伯恩！
Butcher shop, 2:00! dude has a phone!
2點鐘方向有家肉店，老闆拿著手機！
Why is Eldridge running?
艾綴奇為啥要跑？
- Make him put it down!    - Put down the phone!
- 命令他放下手機！    - 放下手機！
Come on, guys, talk to me,
快點，夥計們，告訴我怎麼了
Drop the phone! Drop your phone!
手機扔掉！手機扔掉！
Hey, burn him, Eldridge! Burn him!
開槍打他，艾綴奇，射他！
- Put down the cell phone!    - Eldridge, burn him!
- 放下手機    - 艾綴奇，打他！
- Get out of the way,    - Drop your phone!
- 讓開    - 交出你的手機！
Make him put it down! Go get it!
命令他放下手機！ 去拿過來！
- Come on, Eldridge!    - I can't get him shot!
- 快點，艾綴奇！    - 我不能開槍
Thompson!
湯普森！
Anywhere's good,
放哪兒都行
- Is that everything?    - Yeah,
- 都在這兒了？    - 是
Yeah?
誰啊？
Come in.
進來
Sergeant James?
詹姆斯上士！
JT Sanborn, man.
我是J.T.桑伯恩
Hey! Hi, how are you? Will.
你好，我叫威爾
Welcome to Bravo Company; welcome to Camp Victory,
歡迎來勝利營B連！
Camp Victory? I thought this was Camp Liberty,
勝利營？我應該在自由營…
Oh! No, they changed that about a week ago.
哦，名字是一周前換的
Victory sounds better.
勝利聽上去更順耳
- All right. Well, at least I'm in the right place, right?    - Yeah,
- 好吧，至少我沒走錯地方    - 沒錯
While you're here, can you help me move this thing real quick?
既然你來了，能幫我搭把手嗎？
Yeah, no problem.
沒問題
Maybe you shouldn't take this down.
也許你不該把它扒下來
We get a lot of mortars at night.
晚上常有迫擊炮襲擊
The plywood on the windows help with the lateral fray coming through.
窗口這些夾板可以擋住側飛的彈片
That's why it's up there.
所以才裝在這兒
Yeah, well, it's not going to stop a mortar round
要是榴彈從天花板飛下來
from coming in through the roof, you know.
這東西就沒用了
Besides, I like the sunshine.
而且我喜歡陽光
Hey, I'm sorry to hear about Thompson.
湯姆森的事我聽說了，真遺憾
- I know he was a good tech.    - Yeah, he was,
- 我知道他拆彈很在行    - 是的
He was a great team leader, too,
他帶隊也很在行
Yeah, I'm not trying to fill his shoes or anything,
我沒想做個完美的接班人
I'm just... I'm just going to do my best.
我只想…只想盡力而為
- Appreciate it,    - All right.
- 明白    - 那好
Cool
好得很
Home sweet home, right?
還是自己的窩最好啊
Aren't you glad the Army has all these tanks parked here?
看到我軍在這兒停了這麼多坦克 你笑得出來麼？
Just in case the Russians come we have to have a big tank battle.
就為了提防俄國佬來襲 到時候大家來一場坦克大戰
I'd rather be on the side with the tanks, just in case, rather than not have them.
我寧願備著這些坦克，以防萬一 有總比沒有好
Yeah, but they don't do anything.
是，但這些傢伙根本沒用
Anyone comes alongside a Humvee we're dead.
如果有人朝這悍馬車跑過來 我們就死定了
Anybody even looks at you funny we're dead,
如果有人奇怪地看著你，我們就死定了
Pretty much the bottom line is if you're in Iraq, you're dead.
差不多可以這麼說 如果你來伊拉克，你就死定了
How's a fuckin' tank supposed to stop that?
這鳥坦克能救你的小命麼？
- Would you shut up, Owen please?    - Sorry
- 歐文，能不能閉嘴？    - 抱歉
Just trying to scare the new guy.
我只是想嚇嚇新人
I saw a little bit in Afghanistan, too.
在阿富汗的時候我也見識過
- Get your eyes on the road, Eldridge.    - Copy that
- 到外面看看路況，艾綴奇    - 收到
Yalla!
讓開！
Blaster One, this is Victory Main.
拆彈一號，我是勝利總部
Have you reached your 10-20, yet? Over.
是否抵達座標10-20？完畢
Where the hell are the guys who called this in?
那些叫我們來的傢伙都去哪兒了？
Victory Main, Victory Main, this is Blaster Mike.
勝利總部，我是拆彈邁克
Interrogative, do you have an update on position? Over.
地點似乎不對，是否有更新信息？完畢
Victory Main, figures to follow, Three-four-five-three is your grid.
我是勝利總部，座標位於3、4、5、3
Well, that's exactly where the hell I am and I don't see anybody in fatigues,
我現在就站在這鬼地方 但不見任何需援助人員
Give us a second to confirm.
稍等，正在確定坐標
Watch your feet!
留神腳下
Set visual is three-four five-three,
查看座標…3…4…5…3…完畢
Got the Humvee
看到悍馬車了
Friendly!
友軍！
Ah, here we go.
啊，在這兒
They abandoned their vehicle.
他們棄車了
We got an empty Humvee over here, James.
詹姆斯，這兒有輛悍馬，但裡面沒人
Yeah, I got it.
嗯，我知道了
Let's move.
我們走
Friendly,
友軍
- Morning, boys.    - Sir.
- 早上好，小伙子們    - 長官好
Don't tell me the bomb's in here with you guys.
別告訴我炸彈和你們在一起
- Step out and I'll show you what's going on    - All right
- 借一步，我告訴你發生了什麼    - 好
Down on that block 20 meters.
那個街區往前20米
This side of the mosque. east side of the street.
在清真寺這邊，路的東邊
our informant says he saw a pair of wires
我們的線人說他看到一堆引線
going into a rubble pile
線頭埋在一個碎石堆裡
- It's a possible IED.    - Yeah
- 很可能是土製炸彈    - 恩
- I trust this guy. I know him.    - Okay,
- 那個線人我瞭解，我相信他的判斷    - 好的
- I'll handle it.    - Do you want to talk him or...    - No.
- 我來處理    - 你需要和他談談嗎？    - 不用了
Good, Keep your boys back, We'll be good, Thank you,
好 帶著你的兄弟靠後站 由我們來處理 謝謝
Specialist, bring up the Humvee,
技術兵，把悍馬車開過來
What's going on?
怎麼了？
I'm going to break out the suit.
我要穿上拆彈服
- What about the bot?    - I'll take care of it.
- 那機器人呢？    - 我來就好了
Don't you want to send the bot down there to see what it looks like?
不想讓機器人先去看看情況？
I'll handle it.
我去搞定就行
That's kind of tight down here, James.
詹姆斯，那兒的情況似乎不妙啊
Ready?
準備好了？
Good?
沒問題吧？
You don't have to go down there, We already have the bot halfway up.
你沒必要自己去，有機器人可以代勞
I'll be all right.
沒事
First day, figure you want to take it easy, right?
今天第一天，你想來個輕鬆的，對不對？
How's it looking, Eldridge?
怎麼樣了，艾綴奇？
- Good to go    - Let's do it
- 可以出發了    - 開始吧
- Got tools?    - Got tools
- 工具在裡面？    - 在裡面
All right. Let's rock and roll, man.
好吧，我們上路
- He's a rowdy boy    - He's reckless
- 真是個急躁的小子    - 是魯莽
Blaster One, what's going on?
拆彈1號，發生了什麼事情？
Blaster One! What are you doing?
拆彈1號！你在搞什麼？
Blaster One, this is Blaster Mike
拆彈1號，這裡是拆彈邁克
What's with the smoke on the side of the road?
這路上的煙是怎麼回事，完畢
Hey, James, can you hear me?
嘿詹姆斯，能聽見嗎？
Creating a diversion
我在聲東擊西
From what? Is there a threat?
對誰？你發現威脅了？
Eldridge, get up on the wall, Move!
艾綴奇，上牆，快點！
Tell me what you see, specialist
看到什麼了，技術兵？
All right, I got him
哦，我看到他了
He's walking down range.
他正走出射程
James, the smoke is killing my visibility.
詹姆斯，煙霧完全阻擋了視線
Where are you in relationship to the IED? Are you within 100 meters yet?
你和那炸彈差多遠？到沒到100米？
Hell, I don't know, but I'll tell you when I'm standing over it, cowboy.
我怎麼知道 如果踩到了炸彈，我會告訴你的
Take cover!
注意掩護！
Oh, no, A car stopped in front of him, Sanborn.
哦，不，有輛車停在他面前，桑伯恩！
Shit, James! James, come back now.
該死，詹姆斯！詹姆斯，快回來，快
EOD pulled a nine on this Haji in a car.
排爆小組的人拿著9毫米手槍 對著車裡的伊斯蘭佬
Want me to send backup?
要派增援嗎？
I got it.
我對付就行了
- Sanchez, Hayes!    - Negative! Negative!
- 桑切斯，海耶斯！    - 不要，不要
Stand down
留在原地
The blast will come up the block
爆炸會波及大片街區
Stay clear around the corner
呆在街角別動
EOD has the situation under control, over
這兒由排爆小組負責，完畢
- Where you going?    - Hold your fire on my command!
- 你要上哪兒去？    - 沒有我命令，不許開槍！
Want to back up?
想倒車嗎？
Get out of the car!
下車！
- Get out of the car!    - Come on!
- 下車！    - 快點!
What the fuck are you doing?
你他媽想幹嘛？
Back up!
往後退！
Hello?
喂？
Want to get back?
想退回去麼？
It's that way.
往那邊走
Back
回去
Taxi's moving.
計程車開了
Get out of the car!
從車上面下來！
Stop! Stop the car!
停車！把車停下！
- Get out, get out of the fucking car!    - Get out the ground!
- 下來，從上面下來！   - 趴在地下！
- Underground!    - Stay down!
- 趴下!    - 不許動！
Well, if he wasn't an insurgent, he sure the hell is now.
如果他以前不是叛亂分子 那現在總該算了吧
Roger that! That's real funny.
收到，你的話真有趣…
Got something
我發現了些東西
Oh, baby!
嘿，小親親
Gotcha
找到了
All right
好了
We're done
完事了
Good to go
可以引爆了，可以引爆了
Come down, specialist.
下來，技術兵
Roger
收到
Got a wire
又發現一根線
Hang on
等等
Where are you going?
你這是要去哪兒啊？
Secondary
還有其他的
Shit
媽的
Take cover! Get in the wall! Get in the wall!
找掩護，躲到牆後面去！
That wasn't so bad. First time working together. What do you think?
初次合作還不錯，你覺得呢？
I think us working together means I talk to you and you talk to me
我有情況告訴你，你有情況告訴我 這才叫合作
- We going on a date, Sanborn?    - No
- 我們是在約會嗎，桑伯恩？    - 不
We're going on a mission.
我們是在完成任務
and my job is to keep you safe so we can keep going on missions.
我負責保護你的安全 這樣我們才好繼續執行其他任務
It's combat, buddy.
這是戰鬥，夥計
Hey,
嘿
It's just 39 days.
只剩39天了
Thirty-eight if we survive today.
如果今天不死的話，還剩38天
Hey, it's ''Mr., Be All You Can Be''!
是你啊，「盡我所能」先生
What's up, doc?
有甚麼新聞嗎，醫生？
Not much, How are you?
沒什麼，你怎麼樣？
I'm good.
我很好
Got a question about that song, ''Be All You Can Be''.
有個問題,關於那首歌「盡我所能」
What if all I can be is dead on the side of an Iraqi road?
如果盡我所能的結果是橫屍伊拉克街頭 那我怎麼辦？
I mean, I think it's logical.
這事不是沒有可能
This is war, people die all the time. Why not me?
這是戰爭，每天都有人死 當然可能也會落到我頭上
You got to change the record in our head.
你必須換一種想法
You gotta start thinking about other things.
你得去想些其他的東西
Okay, Stop obsessing... Right now.
別老想這個了
What are you thinking about?
現在你在想什麼？
You want to know what I'm thinking about, doc?     - Yeah
- 我在想什麼，你想知道嘛？    - 是的
This is what I'm thinking about, doc.
我在想的就是這個
Here's Thompson, okay. He's dead, he's alive.
地下躺著湯姆森… 他死了，他沒死
He's dead. He's alive.
他死了，他沒死
Yo, what's up, my nigger? What's up, man? You cool?
嘿，最近如何，你好嗎？
Come on, You want the cool shit? Come on, come on, It's the tight shit, man,
想要好貨麼？看看嘛，這貨很正的
Wanna buy DVD? Wanna buy DVD?
要買DVD嗎？要買DVD嗎？
Fuck you, Come, come, please, please1
去你的…別這樣，拜託！
New releases, look.
是新片！
Hello, Hello! Want to buy DVDs? Very good, Very good,
你好你好，要DVD嗎？絕贊絕讚的！
How much?
多少錢？
One for five and two for nine,
5元一張，9元兩張
Three for twelve.
三張12元怎麼樣？
Three for thirteen and I don't give you tax. Very good, man. Look.
三張13元，還不加稅 東西非常好，你看看
- Look...    - No tax?
- 看這兒…    - 不加稅？
All right, What do you got? What do you got,
好吧，你有些什麼片子？
You know, you smart shit, You not like those stupid fuck face.
算你丫聰明，不像那些蠢大糞
Yeah, I'm the smart guy.
是啊，我是聰明人
You're a smart kid, Give me your best one, okay?
你是個聰明的孩子 把你的頂級貨給我吧
- Here, this the best one.    - This is a good one?
- 給你，這是頂級的    - 這個就是頂級的？
- Yeah, The best shit, man.    - Okay
- 絕對頂級，老兄    - 好吧
Here you go, I'll take one.
錢給你，我買一張
- Keep the change    - Thank you
- 不用找了    - 謝謝
Want a cigarette?
要香煙嗎？
Get out of here, You shouldn't smoke.
才不給呢，你不該抽煙
Thank you. Take it easy.
謝謝，跟你開個玩笑
I need to talk to you about something before we go out again.
在下次任務之前，我得和你談談
What's that?
要說什麼？
- Yesterday    - Mm-hmm
- 昨天的事    - 恩
Wasn't cool
可不好玩
Yeah, I know. You'll get it, though.
我知道，但你會習慣的，會習慣的
- So, you're a ranger, huh?    - Yeah.
- 這麼說你是個獨行俠？    - 對嘍
I was in intelligence seven years before I joined EOD,
來拆彈組之前，我在情報部門干了7年
We ran missions in every shithole that you could possibly imagine.
我們在各種惡劣情況下執行任務 對此你肯定有概念
So, I'm pretty sure I can figure out a redneck piece of trailer trash like you.
像你這樣居無定所的鄉巴佬 我想我是看得蠻透的
Looks like you're on the right track.
看來你已經開始習慣了
We'll see you out there.
我們在外面等你
Let's go, move!
快走
Shit, Get out of the way. Move!
該死，快讓開
Hello
你好
- Where is it?    - It's behind the wall
- 東西呢？    - 在牆後面
- All right! See any wires? Any smoke?
有沒有看到電線或者煙霧什麼的？
No, I didn't look
不，我沒有細看
So, how do you know it's a bomb?
那你怎麼知道是炸彈？
The car has been parked illegally
那輛車違法停靠在那裡
The suspension is sagging. There's definitely something heavy in the trunk,
而且懸掛特別低，後備箱裡一定有重物
Right. So, why don't you walk over there and peak inside and tell me what you see.
好，不如你現在過去看看 然後告訴我那裡面有什麼
You want me to go close to it?
你要我走過去看？
Yeah! No-no, I don't. I'm kidding.
沒錯…不不，我沒那個意思，開玩笑
Shit
媽的！
It's coming from over here!
槍聲從那兒來！
Blaster One. You there?
拆彈1號，你在嗎？
Blaster One, you hear me?
拆彈1號，聽到了嗎？
Here
拿著
Shit
見鬼
Let's go, guys.
來啊，夥計們
Let it go.
放手
I got top cover.
我去屋頂掩護！
That's a negative, specialist.
不行，技術兵
Eldridge, you stay with me.
艾綴奇，你得跟著我
Sanborn, you take top covers.
桑伯恩，你去屋頂掩護
Shit
該死
Blaster Mike in position
拆彈邁克，到達指定地點
What do you got?
情況如何？
I got a through and through to the chest, but I got him stable.
子彈貫穿了他的胸膛，但不致命
He's not going to make it.
看來他沒希望了
We're leaving in 15 minutes. Got a survival wound, sir.
如果15分鐘內帶他離開 那他的傷還有救，長官
Oh, God.
哦，上帝啊
- What's he doing?    - I don't know,
- 他在幹嘛？    - 我不知道
What are you doing?
你在幹嘛？
There's enough bang in there to send us all to Jesus.
那裡面的炸藥足夠大家一起見上帝了
If I'm going to die, I'm going to die comfortable.
如果要死，我也要死的舒服一些
I need my kit and my cans.
把我的家什都拿來
What's going on down there, Eldridge?
怎麼了，艾綴奇？
I'm getting his kit and his cans. Cover me, please.
我去幫他拿家什，請給我掩護
Kit and cans
給你
Got a Lot of deck cord, electrical
好多導爆線…是電子起爆
I'm looking for this initiating system
我在找起爆裝置
Well, it's not in the back seat.
似乎不在後座裡
I don't think.
我不這麼想
All right, It's not in the back seat.
好了，它不在後座裡
Got a young man on the roof, your 9:00, keep an eye on him.
有個年輕人在屋頂，9點鐘方向，盯住了
Roger that
收到
It's not in the front seat.
也不在前座
It's not in the door.
不在門裡
Not on the floors.
不在地板上
Not in the glove box.
不在手套箱裡
If you haven't found it yet, it's probably under the car.
如果還沒找到，有可能在車下面
Yeah, no wire leads under... the car. It's all in here somewhere.
車下面沒線，肯定藏在車裡
- Hey, Sanborn    - Yeah
- 嘿，桑伯恩    - 怎麼？
You got eyes on some guy, with a video camera?
你剛才是不是看到一個人 手裡拿了攝像機？
No, Where?
沒有啊，在哪兒？
He's right at my 12:00, you see him? He's pointing the fucking thing at me
在我12點鐘方向，看到了嗎？ 他舉著那個鳥東西對著我
- Shit    - Negative, I don't see him.
- 該死    - 沒有，我沒看到他
Hey, Sanborn. He's right at my 12:00, look! 12:00!
桑伯恩，他就在我12點方向
Roger that, I got him.
收到，我看到他了
Getting ready to put me on YouTube.
他想拍下我，然後傳到YOUTUBE上
- Little shady.   - Yeah, he Looks shady. Keep an eye on him,
- 有點可疑啊    - 我也這樣覺得，盯著他。
Okay, So, what's the play?
好，我該怎麼做？
Be smart. Make a good decision, over
放聰明點，別胡來，完畢
Got more wire
這裡線更多
Leads fucking nowhere
通向什麼鬼地方
Fuck!
媽的！
Hey, James, how you doing?
嘿，詹姆斯，你那邊怎麼樣了？
I'm wonderful, How are you?
好極了，你怎麼樣？
You know, we've been here a while
在這兒呆的時間已經夠長的了
We need to get out of here soon.
必須盡快離開這裡
Uh-huh,
哦
We got a lot of eyes on us, James. We need to get out of here.
很多人在看著我們，必須快點離開
Roger that, I might figure this out.
收到，我想我能解決
James, we need to get out of here,
詹姆斯，我們必須快點離開
James, do you copy?
詹姆斯，你聽到了嗎？
Fuck it, I get it.
媽的，我知道了
Fuck me
我靠
- Hey, how's it looking in there, soldier?    - All clear
- 嘿，下面情況怎麼樣？    - 疏散完畢
James, the evac is complete. We can leave.
詹姆斯，人員已疏散完畢，可以撤了
Let the engineers handle this mess,
讓工兵來料理後事吧
- We moving?    - That's affirmative
- 我們撤麼？    - 是的
Interesting
有意思
What's up with James? He's not answering
詹姆斯怎麼回事？他沒回話
Yeah, I think he removed his headset,
呃，他好像摘掉了耳機
Well, will you tell him to put his radio back on, please?
能不能跟他說，讓他戴上耳機？
Hey, James!
嘿，詹姆斯
Sergeant Sanborn is asking if you'll please put your headset back on.
桑伯恩中士問你，能不能戴上耳機
Uh... that's a negative.
呃…他不同意
- That, yeah, that's not gonna happen.    - Shit!
- 他不肯戴上耳機    - 該死的
I got eyes on three guys at the Minaret at 6:00.
清真寺尖塔頂上有3個人，6點鐘方向
- What the hell is he doing?    - I don't know what the fuck he's doing!
- 他到底在幹嘛？    - 我怎麼知道…
Looks like, he's checking the oil.
像是在檢查油箱
They're communicating with your cameraman.
他們在和攝像的男人聯絡
This is real bad, man.
不妙啊，老兄
Get behind the Jersey barrier.
蹲到護欄後面去
I can't see James from here.
在這裡我看不到詹姆斯
Get down now!
馬上給我蹲下！
We can go!
可以走了！
Bastard
王八蛋
We're done.
活幹完了
Sanborn, let's get out of here.
桑伯恩，我們走！
Woo
喔
That was good.
真爽
- Hey, James!    - What?
- 嘿，詹姆斯    - 嗯？
Never turn your headset off again.
再也不許摘掉耳機
You the guy in the bomb suit?
你就是那個拆彈員？
No, sir, Sir, that's Sergeant James. He's right here.
不，長官，是詹姆斯上士，他在那裡
- Hey, James.    - Yeah?
- 嘿，詹姆斯    - 嗯？
Someone's here to see you.
有人找你
You the guy in the flaming car. Sergeant James?
搞定起火轎車的那個就是你？
Afternoon, sir Uh, yes, sir
下午好，是我幹的，長官
Well, that's just hot shit.
好，簡直太棒了
You're a wild man, you know that?
你是個強人，知道嗎？
- Uh, yes, sir    - He's a wild man
- 是的，長官    - 他是個強人
You know that?
你們知道嗎？
I want to shake your hand.
我想和你握手
- Thank you, sir.    - Yeah
- 謝謝長官    - 好
How many bombs have you disarmed?
你拆過多少炸彈？
Uh, I'm not quite sure.
啊，我不是很確定…
- Sergeant?    - Yes, sir.
- 上士！    - 是，長官
I asked you a question.
我在問你問題
Eight hundred seventy-three, sir.
873個，長官
Eight hundred! And seventy-three.
八百！七十三！
That's just hot shit.
簡直棒到沒話說
- Counting today, sir, yes.    - That's gotta be a record.
- 今天的也算在裡面了，是嗎？    - 這一定是最高記錄
What's the best way to... go about disarming one of these things?
拆這些鬼東西…最好的方法是什麼？
The way you don't die, sir.
是活著拆了它，長官
That's a good one.
呵呵，是個好方法
That's spoken like a wild man. That's good.
強人就該這麼說話，真不錯
- Hey, what's up, man?    - Oh, hey, wait a minute,
- 你好啊    - 嘿嘿，等一下
Look who it is.
看看這是誰啊？
I want my five bucks back, buddy.
把5元錢還給我，老弟
Five dollars for what, man? You crazy now?
什麼5元錢？你發癡啊？
Yeah, The DVD you sold me was crap.
你賣給我的DVD是什麼狗屁東西！
You crazy, man. That's impossible. It's Hollywood special effects.
你胡說，不可能，那是好萊塢特技
No, It was shaky. It was out of focus, buddy.
畫面不僅晃，還一片模糊
- What, you want donkey porn?    - It's crap.
- 那你要看什麼，獸交？    - 那片子是垃圾
Girls on dog? Gay sex, man?
女人和狗做？還是男同志片？
Anything you want, you get.
你要什麼，就給你什麼
I hook you up, man.
我跟你，那是啥關係
All right, What... what's your name?
哈哈哈哈，好吧，你叫什麼名字？
- Beckham.    - Beckham like the soccer player?
-貝克漢姆    -貝克漢姆？那個足球運動員？
Yeah, man. It's like soccer player. Now give me my ball.
就是那個足球明星，把球還給我
Are you a soccer player?
你是足球運動員？
Yeah, man, Best of the best. I'm better than Beckham.
是的，我是王中王，比貝克漢姆還強
- You play goalie?    - Yes, I play goalie    - Good
- 你會守門麼？    - 是的，我會    - 好
I'll make you a deal. If you can stop the ball, I'm going to give you five bucks,
那我們來賭一場，如果你能守住我的球 我就再給你5塊錢
- but if you can't...    - And what if... what if I can't?
- 但如果你沒守住…    - 沒守住怎麼樣？
Listen to me. If I score, I'm going to keep your ball,
如果我射進你的門，這球就歸我
- Deal?    - Deal
- 成不成？    - 成
Get up there
過去吧
Go on
走啊
- Let's see what you got hot stuff    - Are you ready?
- 看看你有什麼能耐    - 準備好了嗎？
On three, Ready?
我數到3，你準備好了嗎？
One, two, three... Aahh!
1…2…3！啊…
Shit
該死
Come on Where's the five dollars? Man, come on.
快點，我的5塊錢呢？
All right, I got ya. Good job, dude.
好吧，我給你，不錯嘛，年輕人
Here's five.
五塊錢給你
You're an EOD, boomala, boomala.
你是拆彈組的？
That's right.
沒錯
It's fun, no?
那很有趣吧？
It's cool? It's gangster.
好像黑幫一樣，對不對？
- Yeah?    - Yeah, I think so.
- 是吧    - 差不多吧
Tell you what, I'm going to buy...
那什麼，我要買…
Let me see if I have enough money, yeah. Five.
讓我看看錢夠不夠…好，夠五塊錢
I'm going to buy another DVD, okay?
我要再買張DVD
But if it's shaky... Look at me... or out of focus...
但如果還是晃，或者畫面模糊
or any way not 100%,
或者不是百分百的好片
I'm going to chop off your god dammed head with a dull knife.
我就拿把鈍刀，把你的小腦瓜子鋸下來
How do you feel about that? I'm just kidding.
怕了吧？我只是開玩笑，開玩笑
Here, you're a good kid, man. You're a good kid, aren't ya?
你是個好娃娃，真是個好娃娃
Owen
歐文！
Hi
嗨！
- Hi, sir,    - How are you?
- 你好，長官！    - 怎麼樣？
- I'm good    - Good
- 不錯    - 很好
- What's wrong?    - Brakes are squeaking
- 哪裡壞了？    - 剎車的聲音不對
Don't trust the mechanics around here. You know.
這裡的機修工不太靠得住
- So, how you doing?    - Good
- 最近怎麼樣？    - 我很好
I just want to check the oil.
我去檢查下油箱
Yeah, it's good to sleep, eating well...
吃得也好，睡得也香
I'm feeling pretty squared away, actually, doc.
感覺整個人神清氣爽，真的
Good to hear it.
聽你這麼說，我很高興
So, you getting along with the other soldiers in your unit?
和同部隊的戰友相處得還好麼？
Yeah, My team's great. My team Leader is inspiring.
嗯，我們隊很棒，隊長很會鼓舞人
- Are you being sarcastic, soldier?    - No
- 你是在說反話麼？    - 沒有
He's going to get me killed.
他正打算送我歸西呢
almost died yesterday.
昨天差點就成功了
At least I'll die in the line of duty, proud and strong.
至少是因公殉職，我感到很自豪很光榮
You know, this doesn't have to be a bad time in your life.
這不是你人生的低谷
Going to war is a - is a once in a lifetime experience.
參戰是你一生中難得的經歷
It could be fun.
也許可以很有趣
And you know this from your extensive work in the field, right?
是豐富的實戰經驗讓你得出這些結論的麼？
I've done my field duty.
我已履行了我的兵役
Where's that? Yale?
在哪兒服的役？耶魯大學？
Look, you don't want me to come around, I won't come around.
如果你不想和我談，我可以不來找你
These talks are voluntary.
我是出於志願才來幫你
Look, I'm sorry.
我很抱歉
I appreciate what you're saying, I do.
你能跟我說這些，我很感激，真的
I appreciate our sessions together,
我也很感謝你給我的心理治療
but you need to come out from behind the wire, see what we do.
但你也需要走到前方去看看 看看我們在做的事情
Well,
好吧
if this circumstance calls for it, I will.
如果情況需要，我會去的
Just like every other soldier.
就像別的士兵一樣
Fire in the hole!
目標起爆！
Firing now!
起爆！
- Ready for second det?    - Ready
- 準備好第二次爆炸了沒？    - 準備好了
Fire in the hole! Fire in the hole, Fire in the hole!
目標起爆！目標起爆！目標起爆！
Whoa, whoa, whoa, Hold on a second!
喂喂喂，等一下
God damn it, I think it forgot my gloves down there.
天殺的，我好像把手套忘在那裡了
- What?    - I forgot my gloves.
- 什麼？    - 我忘拿手套了
Hang on
等一下
You know, these detonators misfire all the time.
這些引爆器很容易誤爆啊
What are you doing?
你是甚麼意思？
I'm just saying shit happens, they misfire.
我只是說，總免不了有倒霉事 比如可能發生誤爆
He'd be obliterated to nothing,
他會被炸成粉粉面面的
His helmet would be left, You could have that.
也許能剩個頭盔，那就歸你好了
Little specs of hair, charred on the inside.
還有幾縷頭髮，內層或許會有些焦
Yeah, there'd be half a helmet somewhere,
是啊，也許能找到半個頭盔
bits of hair.
還有一點點頭髮
Ask for a change in technique and protocol,
然後我們要求改進技術流程
make sure this type of accident never happen again, you know?
以確保此類事故不再發生
You'd have to write the report.
這樣的話，你得寫一份報告
- Are you serious?    - I can't write it.
- 你是認真的嗎？    - 我寫不來的
No, I mean, are you serious about killing him?
不，我是問你，真想殺了他？
- Twelve o'clock I see an SUV    - Roger that
- 12點鐘方向有一輛SUV越野車    - 收到
I got four armed men.
我看到4個全副武裝的傢伙
They're in Haji gear.
伊斯蘭的裝扮
All right, go slow and easy.
好，慢慢靠過去
Careful now.
停車
All right, Careful now, guys.
好，各位小心點
- Eldridge, you stay on that 50.    - I got 'em.
- 艾綴奇，你守好機槍    - 我把著呢
''Obre... obre...'' put your gun down!
放下槍，放下你們的槍
On your knees! Put your gun down!
跪在地上，放下槍！
- Obre, motherfucker!    - Hold up your hands!
- 混蛋    - 把手舉高
Get down, motherfucker, Obre!
跪下！ 混蛋
Put your gun down now!
快把槍放到地上！
Put your gun down!
把槍放下！
Advance, advance...
前進，前進
Hands high!
手舉高！
- Eldridge, cover!    - I got you
- 艾綴奇，掩護！    - 明白
Pistol, off your hip, now!
把背後的手槍扔掉，快點！
What you want me to do?
到底要我幹嘛？
Keep my hands up or take off the pistol?
把手舉高還是扔掉手槍？
- Keep your hands up    - Okay
- 舉著你的手    - 好
Easy, easy.
慢點，慢點
Got it!
拿到
Can I touch my fucking head now?
我可以碰自己的腦袋嗎？
Slowly
慢一點
We're on the same fucking side, guys.
夥計們，我們是一條戰線的
Jesus
哦，上帝
You guys are wired fucking tight, you know that?
你們實在有點草木皆兵了
Well, this is no place for a picnic, right. What are you guys doing here?
這裡可不是野餐的地方，你們在這裡幹嘛？
We have a flat tire, can you help us?
我們的車胎爆了，能幫我們嗎？
Sure, yeah. You got any spares?
沒問題，你們有備胎嗎？
We have spares, but we've used up our wrench.
備胎是有，可我們的扳手用光了
How do you use up a wrench?
扳手怎麼會用光的？
Well, the uh, the guy over there with the red thing on his head,
呃…那個包著紅頭巾的男人
he threw it at someone.
他拿扳手當飛鏢使了
- All right    - Thank you
- 呵，好吧    - 謝謝
That's Chris, this is the wrench man.
這是克裡斯，這是扳手男
- Hello, wrench man.    - That's Jimmy.
- 你好，扳手男    - 那個是傑米
You know, you can shoot people here, you don't have to throw a wrench at 'em,
在這裡你可以用槍打，不用扔扳手
Fuck off
去你的
Take a look at this,
看看這個
I picked these guys up in Najaf.
這些人是在納傑夫(伊拉克聖城)抓的
Nine of hearts, that's one,
這個是紅心9號通緝犯
And the other... jack of clubs,
另外一個，就是梅花J
- These the same guys?    - Yep, That's them.
- 就是他們？    - 沒錯，就是他們
Does he need a little help there?
他需要幫忙嗎？
What's the problem with the tire? Come on.
輪胎到底什麼問題？快點！
No good, boss. This wrench is too small.
這個不行，老大，這個太小了
All right, solutions? Anyone?
誰有解決辦法嗎？
I think there's another wrench in the back of the Humvee if you want to check,
在悍馬車後好像還有把扳手
- I'll give it a try.    - All right. Let's do it.
- 那我試試看吧    - 好，快點干
How long you guys out here?
你們來這裡多久了？
Well, I don't know. Specialist, what do we got?
我不知道，技術兵，我們來多久了？
- We have... 23 more days or 22... - Oh yeah
還有23天吧…不對，還剩22天就…
No one's counting.
沒人仔細算過
Contact left!
左邊接敵！
Take cover!
找掩護！
Chris, take the 50. Jimmy, take that in the Humvee.
克裡斯，上機槍 吉米，拿悍馬車裡的傢伙
- Got it.    - Come on!
- 明白    - 快點！
Charlie, go!
查理，走！
Go, go, go!
走！走！
Fucking morons!
混賬東西
Get on the side, Charlie Get the Barret and the go-bag, Jimmy.
查理，保護側翼 傑米，把狙擊槍和衝鋒包拿來
- What are we shooting at?    - I don't know.
- 我們在打誰？    - 我怎麼知道
Fuck, the packages are gone!
媽的，通緝犯跑啦！
They won't get far on foot.
他們跑不遠的
Bring 'em back those fuckers now. I'm out 500,000 fucking pounds.
把那倆給我逮回來 不能讓50萬元就這麼飛了
I forgot,
哈哈，我忘了
it's 500,000 dead or alive.
無論生死，都值50萬
- Okay Jimmy, give me the Barret.    - Yeah
- 傑米，把巴雷特狙擊槍給我    - 好
I can't see a thing.
我什麼也看不見
Come on!
來吧！
Chris is shooting wild. Gotta conserve the ammo.
克裡斯在亂射…得節約子彈啊
Hey, Chris can you hear me?
克裡斯，聽到我說話嗎？
Hey, Chris! Chris! Can you hear me? Chill out on the 50!
克裡斯！聽見沒？別一個勁開槍！
Roger that.
收到！
- Fifty's down    - They shot Chris.
- 機槍啞火了！    - 克裡斯被擊中了
It must be coming from that building.
子彈一定是從那房子裡出來的
I can't see anything.
我什麼也看不見
Movement on the roof.
有人在房頂移動
Yeah?
怎麼樣？
Three meters higher.
再抬高3米
I'm going to adjust.
我調整一下
Fuck
媽的
Fuck, he's dead.
媽的，他死了
We've got to get out of here now!
我們必須馬上離開這裡
Damm it.
媽的！
This is Alpha Nine. We're in deep shit.
這裡是阿爾法9，情況危急
I'll get on the Barret.
我去狙擊
Go, go, go!
走，走！
Yeah, we're taking incoming fire.
是，我們受到攻擊
- No, Sanborn, don't come up here    - Got it!
- 桑伯恩，別上去    - 收到
Go, buddy, Stay low! Stay Low!
過去，夥計，壓低身體！
I have two KIA,
我方傷亡2人
correction, three KIA... our grid last lock stat...
更正，傷亡3人…現處方位是…
Stay low!
身體壓低！
Can you get me some help?
能幫我一下麼？
Copy, Alpha Nine. Hold on, over.
收到，阿爾法9，請稍候，完畢
- Behind you    - Yeah
- 我來了    - 好
Breathe easy
放鬆
- I got movement    - Yeah
- 發現人影    - 嗯
On the ridge of that house
在房頂上
Eight hundred and fifty meters
距離850米
- See it    - By the window
- 看見了    - 在窗邊…
- You got target    - Got it
- 有個目標    - 看見了
All right, here little left.
有點偏左
Just breathe easy
放鬆
- I'm out of ammo - Hmm?
沒子彈了
I'm out of ammo.
我沒子彈了
Eldridge, we need ammo.
艾綴奇，我們需要子彈！
Where is it?
子彈在哪裡？
Check on the dead guy, man.
在那死人身上翻翻看
It's on the dead man.
在死人身上
Eldridge!
艾綴奇！
I'm looking.
我在找！
We need that ammo, man.
我們要子彈！
All right, man.
知道了
Oh, here.
好，找到了
Thanks
謝謝
All right. Got it.
好了
Same target.
目標不變
It's fucking jammed.
媽的，卡殼了
Let me see it.
讓我看看
Fuck!
媽的
Aw, shit. The blood's making it jam, Eldridge.
該死，血把子彈卡住了…艾綴奇！
Shit!
該死
You gotta clean the blood off, man. It's making 'em jam.
血把子彈卡住了，把血弄乾淨
Specialist!
技術兵！
- Clean the blood off.    - Okay
- 把血擦乾淨    - 好
Clean it. Clean it.
快點，快點
You gotta clean it, man.
得把它弄乾淨！
- How?    - Spit and rub,
- 怎麼弄？    - 吐口水然後擦！
All right
好吧
Spit and rub, buddy. Spit and rub.
吐口水！然後擦！
It's not working, it's not coming off.
好像沒用，擦不掉
Spit and rub, Spit and rub. Here, take it out.
給我，先把子彈拿出來
- Use your camel, Use your camel.    -  Where is it?
- 用你的水管夾，用水管夾擦    - 在那裡？
You all right?
你還好吧？
Here, use that.
就用這個
Just breathe, buddy.
深呼吸
Come on, Just breathe in.
來，放鬆點
Good. Here, squeeze.
好，拿著，用它擦
- Got it?    - Yeah
- 明白了？    - 明白
Rub that olive, baby. Come on, you got it.
擦乾淨點，小子…嗯，你做的很好
You're doing good, man. You're doing real good.
你做得很好，真的很棒
- Got 'em?    - Yeah
- 好了嗎？    - 好了
I'm going to keep you safe, buddy, all right?
我會保證你沒事的，夥計
Now let's get these bastards, Scan your sectors.
我們去幹掉這幫混蛋，守好你的位置
Scan your sectors.
守好位置
Kill that fuckin' asshole.
殺了那個混賬東西
Son of a bitch.
狗娘養的
Nice, he's down. 2nd one out of range.
漂亮！撂倒一個，另一個躲起來了
Twenty meters to the right of the building.
屋右側20米有一個
I got him.
我看到了
Fire when ready.
瞄準了就打
He's moving, he's moving. To the building.
他跑了，他跑了，往房子方向跑
- Follow him You got him?    - Got him
- 跟上他，看見沒？    - 看到了
He's down.
他也倒了
Goodnight. Thanks for playing.
晚安，感謝參與
Window, the window. At the window,
窗戶，在窗邊！
He's still there.
他還在那兒
Left window. Left window, Got him?
左邊窗戶，左邊窗戶，看到了嗎？
Got him.
看到了
He's down.
打中了
- Hey, Owen?    - Yeah?
- 嘿，歐文    - 什麼事
Can you grab the juice? out of the pack please?
能不能從包裡拿點果汁過來？
Sure
好的
I think we're out.
好像喝完了
- Got anything left to drink?    - You could try that one.
- 有什麼能喝的嗎？    - 試試那個
Thank you.
謝謝你
Drink, drink it.
喝，喝了它
Things are real quiet.
真安靜啊
Yeah, I don't like it.
是啊，我可不喜歡
- Hey, Will?    - Yeah?
- 嘿，威爾    - 怎麼？
At your six o'clock.
在6點鐘方向
I see movement on the bridge. Right on the tracks.
我看到橋上有動靜！就在小路上
Well, handle it.
搞定他
Should I fire?
我該開槍嗎？
It's your call, buddy.
自己決定，夥計
Good job.
幹得好
Hey, Sanborn.
嘿，桑伯恩
I think we're done.
我想應該完事了
Okay? You all right?
你沒事吧？
That's what you get for hitting your fucking team leader, motherfucker.
狗東西，竟敢打隊長，這就是報應
- Man    - I'll be right back, I gotta piss.
我馬上回來，去撒尿
Owen. Another round, boy. That's your order.
歐文！再喝一圈，這是命令！
Well, yes, sir. Sgt, James, sir.
是，長官！
You're not very good with people, are you, sir?
你不太懂相處之道吧，長官
But you're a good warrior, Give me your mug.
但你是名出色的勇士，杯子拿來
There ya go, sir.
喝，長官
You were well on the field of battle today, specialist.
你今天的實戰表現非常出色，技術兵
Cheers
乾杯
Uh, I'm too old for this shit.
老了，喝不動了
- I was scared.    - Yeah?
- 我很害怕    - 是嗎？
Well, everyone's a coward about something, you know.
每個人心裡都有恐懼
You're good. You're real good.
你是好樣的，真是好樣的
Just what do we have here?
看看這裡有什麼？
Will has possessions.
威爾有個小寶箱
I didn't know you owned anything, Will.
我從不知道你有這麼多存貨啊，威爾
Let's see what you got here, Will.
看看都有些什麼
Who is that?
這是誰？
That's my son,
是我兒子
he's a tough little bastard, nothing like me.
他是個難惹的小傢伙，不像我
You mean to tell me you married?
你不會是想告訴我，你結婚了吧？
Well, you know, I had a girlfriend and...
我曾經有個女朋友…
she got pregnant, so we got married.
後來她懷孕了，所以我們結婚了
We got divorced.
後來離了
Or I thought we got divorced.
或者說，我認為我們已經離了
She's still living in the house. And she says we're still together,
她還住在我家，她說我們還是一對
so I don't know, What does that make her?
我就糊塗了，不知道該稱呼她什麼
Dumb for still being with your ass.
抱著你這種傢伙不肯放 不如叫她呆瓜好了
Hey
嘿！
She ain't fuckin' dumb, all right?
她一點也不呆，聽見沒？
She's just loyal.
她很忠誠
She's just loyal. That's all, How 'bout you guys?
是很忠誠…僅此而已 說說你們的事吧
You got... you got a girl? What do you got?
你…你有女人嗎？
My only problem is the girl I do like,
我的問題是，我真正愛的女人
I can't stop her from talking about babies, man.
老是跟我談孩子，我沒轍了
Well, give her your sperm, stud.
那就把你的後代給她啊，種馬
Go on. Do it.
去吧，就這麼做
- C'mon, chicken. Just give it to her.    - No! Hell no!
- 快點，膽小鬼，給她就行了嘛    - 不，絕對不行
Make babies
生孩子去
I know when I'm ready, and I ain't ready for that yet, I know that.
我心裡有數，我現在還沒準備好
Well, well... what do we have here?
哦…看哪，這是什麼？
Uh, components.
呃…是零件
They're bomb parts, signatures.
是炸彈的組件，每個都代表著一個炸彈
Yeah, I see that, but what they doing under your bed?
是，我明白，為什麼會在你床下面
Well...
呃
Ah-ha, there we go, this one...
看這個
This one is from the UN building.
從一幢聯合國大樓拆來的
Flaming car, dead man's switch... Boom,
爆炸車輛，人體起爆
This guy was great, I like him.
這傢伙人不錯，我喜歡
Ah... Look at this one.
看看這個
This one, y'all, is from our first call together.
這來自我們第一次做的任務
This box is full of stuff that almost killed me.
這盒子裡的東西都曾差點要了我的命
And what about this one?
這又是什麼呢？
- Where's this one from, Will?    - It's my wedding ring.
- 這東西從哪兒來的，威爾？    - 這是我的結婚戒指
Like I said, stuff that almost killed me.
我說了，這東西差點殺了我
You know, I just think it's really interesting
我覺得這很有趣
to hold something in your hand that could have killed anyone.
決定許多人生死權的東西 就握在你的手裡
Damn that, It's all shit from radio shack.
去你的，都是些從電子市場買來的破爛
It's interesting.
我覺得很有趣
I think it's interesting too.
我也覺得這很有趣
Well, I think you hit me harder than I hit you
另外，我還沒對你怎麼樣呢
therefore I owe you a punch.
你就先對我下重手，不公平
Now get your ass up, C'mon.
快起來，混球！
C'mon, He's right. Let's go, C'mon,
他說的沒錯，起來
Come on!
來啊
All right, hold on, boys. We need some rules,
好吧夥計們，我先說規則
Sanborn, no face shots.
桑伯恩，不能打臉
Oh, there's gonna be a face shot.
喔，我非得打臉不可
Sergeant James, take off your shirt.
詹姆斯上士，把T恤脫掉
Yes, sir.
是，長官
What happened?
這怎麼搞的？
My momma dropped me when I was a baby,
小時候被我媽摔過
Looks like frag scars,
我看像彈片造成的傷疤
- Let it go, Eldridge, C'mon,    - All right,
- 讓開，艾綴奇    - 好吧
Nice and big
來一記漂亮的重拳
Oohh!
喔~
You like that, huh?
很享受吧？
That's all you got?
你就這點本事？
Come on,
來吧
Bring some, C'mon,
打我，快！
Ooh!
嗚噢！
Wooh, God damn!
嗚，爽耶！
That's gotta hurt.
夠他受的
- You all right, man?    - Oh, yeah
- 你沒事吧，夥計？    - 沒事
- Oh, he's all right.    - Get up, bitch.
- 他還行    - 起來，婊子
All right, bitch.
好了，婊子
- What do you got now?    - Get the fuck off me?
- 看你還有什麼本事？    - 滾開
- What do you got?    - Get off me, you mother fucker.
- 還有什麼本事？    - 從我身上滾開
What do you got? What do you got?
有什麼？什麼？
Wooh, he's a wild one. We got a wild one.
他真騷，太騷了
C'mon, Sanborn. Get him. That's right.
來，桑伯恩，對，就這樣
- Ride him, baby.    - Get off me
- 騎上馬兒跑啊    - 從我身上下來，變態
- C'mon, bitch    - C'mon, guys
- 動啊，婊子    - 好了，夥計們
What do you got?
有啥能耐啊？
Get off me
滾開
Hey, hey, hey!
好了好了
I'm just kidding, motherfucker, shit!
我跟你開玩笑呢，小畜生
You're all right, Sanborn.
你不簡單啊，桑伯恩
You're all right, man.
真的不簡單，兄弟
Owen, get this guy a drink. C'mon.
歐文，給他來點酒，去
- You got him?    - Yeah, I got him,
- 你扶住他    - 扶住了
- All right, here.    - All right.
- 好，我閃了    - 好的
- See you later, be safe.    - All right.
- 回見，當心點    - 好的
All right, come on big boy. Damn, boy, you need to get on a diet.
好了大塊頭，我們走…靠，你該減肥了
He hurt his knee,. C'mon, man.
都快站不住了…來
Steps. C'mon.
當心樓梯
Step, step.
一步，兩步
All right, lay down. All right, Get some rest.
好了，躺下，好好休息
Hey, James, you think I got what it takes to put on the suit?
詹姆斯，你說我配得上這身軍裝麼？
Hell, no.
你不配
Night, boy.
晚安，小子
Oh!
哦
- Good morning, Colonel.    - Good morning.
- 早上好，上校    - 早上好
Mind if I ride along? I'm sick to death of sitting behind a desk all the time.
能捎上我麼？老是干文職，悶死我了
- That'd be a privilege.    - Hop in, Colonel.
- 算是給我的恩惠    - 上車吧，上校
Hey, Doc.
你好，醫生
Not to insult your intelligence, sir.
我不是想侮辱你的智商
but if the shit hits the fan, please don't fire out the Humvee.
但如果遇到麻煩，請不要向車外射擊
The round will just bounce around, and someone might get shot.
免得搬起石頭砸自己的腳 有人會吃槍子的
- I don't like getting shot.    - Understood, Sergeant,
- 我可不想吃槍子    - 明白了，上士
Oh, it's a pretty standard mission.
這是個很常規的任務
We're just here to pick up some unexploded ordinance.
我們要去處理一批爆炸軍械
Sergeant James is gonna see what the deal is
詹姆斯上士會去現場看情況
and then hopefully we'll be gone in a couple minutes.
希望能在幾分鐘內搞定
- We've gotta gear up.    - For what?
- 我們得帶上裝備    - 為啥？
Security hasn't gone in.
保安部隊沒進去過
Go in quiet.
我們潛進去
- Radios off, Roger    - Roger that
- 把對講機關掉    - 明白
- Glad you came.    - Stay safe, all right
- 很高興你能來    - 小心點
Clear
沒人
Hey
嘿
cigarette's still smoking.
煙頭還在冒煙
It's all our shit.
這些都是我們的了
Mother fucking goldmine.
都堆成一座金山了
Watch out for trips
小心陷阱
I got something
我發現了些東西
I know this kid
我認識這個孩子
His name's Beckham. He sells DVDs,
他叫貝克漢姆，是賣DVD的
You ever see a body bomb before, man?
以前見過人肉炸彈嗎？
It's disgusting. Let's get outta here,
太噁心了，我們走吧
Hold it.
等下
Eldridge, want you to grab all the C4 and deck cord you can get your hands on.
艾綴奇，帶上所有C4塑膠炸藥 引爆線能拿多少就拿多少
Let's get all this ordnance outta here.
把這裡的彈藥都帶走
And we're just gonna... we're gonna blow the place.
然後我們…我們把這兒炸了
Roger, Just blow it.
明白，就炸了吧
What are you doing?
你們在幹嘛？
Yeah? Putting the stones in to move.
把這些石頭搬上車運走？
Yeah, that's really wonderful
很好
but it's a little bit unsafe today,
但今天有些危險
Yeah, it's a little unsafe.
是的，有些危險
So maybe... I don't know.
也許…
I'm thinking maybe we should move?
…也許我們應該離開？
No?
不行麼？
Fuck
媽的！
- You all right?    - Yeah
- 你沒事吧？    - 是的
- You?    - Yeah
- 你呢？    - 嗯
- You all right, man?    - Yeah
- 沒事吧？    - 嗯
No one in or out, okay?
周圍沒人了吧
Cancel the det, Cancel the det.
取消引爆，取消引爆
- What the fuck is he doing?    - I don't know, man.
- 他在幹嘛？    - 我不知道
I don't know.
我不知道
I'm coming out.
我出來了
Roger that.
收到
- Where are you from?    - New York.
- 你從哪裡來？    - 紐約
The Big Apple.
就是「大蘋果」(紐約暱稱)
I'm from Iraq
我是伊拉克來的
I love it here. This is a beautiful place.
我喜歡這裡，這裡很漂亮
But it's not too safe here, okay?
但是這裡不太安全
So, I think we need - we need to move, please.
所以我認為我們應該離開
You think it's that little Beckham?
那個是營地旁的小孩麼？
No, I don't.
不，我不這麼想
- You're positive?    - Sure.
- 你肯定麼？    - 當然肯定
Hey, I don't know, man. They all look the same, right?
我不知道，他們看上去都一樣
I don't know.
我不知道
- Will seemed sure. That was weird.    - Very weird.
- 威爾似乎很肯定，真是奇怪    - 非常奇怪
Please, just move.
請…離開…
Move, Move.
走，走
Move on. Thank you.
離開…多謝
I'm sorry.
很抱歉
Will's very weird.
威爾這人很怪
I mean he keeps bomb parts under his bed.
把炸彈零件收在床下面
I'll bet you he won't keep any of these parts under his bed.
我打賭，今天的炸彈零件 他可不會收在床下面
Bye-bye
再見
Yeah, bye-bye. Bye, thank you.
再見，謝謝
Hey, Colonel
喂，上校
Let's go
我們走
So long, thank you.
再見，謝謝
IED!
土製炸彈！
Cambridge!
坎布裡奇！
Get back, get down
回來，趴下
Stay back
呆在後面
Stay back, Sanborn, keep 'em back
呆在後面，桑伯恩！讓他們呆著別動
Is anyone hurt?
有人受傷嗎？
Cambridge! Fuck!
坎布裡奇！媽的
Where's Cambridge!
坎布裡奇在哪兒？
Cambridge, come out, We gotta go.
坎布裡奇快點，我們要走了！
Oh, he's dead.
上帝啊，他死了
Hey, we gotta find Cambridge, Doc!
得找到坎布裡奇！醫生！
- Eldridge!    - Doc!
- 艾綴奇    - 醫生！
Eldridge, c'mon, man, C'mon
艾綴奇，來，過來
I just saw him. He was walking right here.
剛才還看見他，從那邊走過來…
I know. He's dead. Look, he's dead, Okay?
我知道，他已經死了，聽著，他死了！
It's all right, man.
沒事了，夥計
It'll be all right, man,.
會好的，夥計
Hello?
喂…
Will?
威爾？
Hey, let me ask you a question,
我有個問題問你
What happened to the little kid? that used to work here?
原來在這裡工作的孩子去哪裡了？
Sorry, man, English I... no English.
對不起，我不會說英語
No-no English, You no speak English now.
你不會說英語？
Little kid, Beckham is his name. He sells... sells DVDs,
那孩子叫貝克漢姆，賣DVD的
DVD, One DVD, $5,
買DVD？1張DVD五元
Oh, Jesus Christ.
上帝啊
- $5    - Excuse me, soldier.
- 五元錢    - 打擾一下
you in charge of this area here?
士兵，你是管這裡的？
- What's up?    - You know this guy?
- 怎麼了？    - 你認識這個人？
How do we know that he's not giving intel to insurgents
如果這個人給叛亂分子提供情報
, telling them where to drop mortars?
告訴他們迫擊炮往哪兒打，怎麼辦？
I think he's just selling DVDs.
他只是個賣DVD的
Well, he's a security risk, We should get rid of him.
這關乎安全問題，該把他趕走
What are you looking at?
看什麼看？
- He's just selling DVDs, man. All the merchants are clear.    - By who?
- 他只是個賣DVD的 這裡所有商販都是清白的    - 誰負責？
I couldn't do anything with him without the say-so from my CO.
沒有上司命令，我不能對他採取任何行動
Okay, Fuck
好吧，媽的
Fuck
媽的
Does this change anything?
是不是不一樣了？
You speak English now. Don't you?
現在你會說英語了，是不是？
- Yalla, yalla, drive!    - Okay
- 開車！    - 好的
- OK    - Is this his house?
- 到了    - 是這棟房子？
Beckham's house?
貝克漢姆的家？
Wait here
在這等著
Fuck
媽的
Psst, psst, shh.
噓…
You speak English?
你說英語嗎？
English, French, Arabic.
英語，法語，阿拉伯語我都會
Good, Open you vest.
好，背心掀開
Ah, stay there. Stay.
呆在那兒，停
Tell me what you know about Beckham.
把貝克漢姆的事情告訴我
For whom?
誰？
Beckham, 12-year-old boy, body bomb. Stay right there
貝克漢姆，12歲的男孩，人肉炸彈 呆著那兒別動
- I don't know    - You don't know
- 我不知道    - 你不知道？
But please, sit down. I am Professor Navid,
請先坐下，我是內韋德教授
This is my home.
這是我家
You are a guest. Please, sit down.
你來了就是客人，請坐吧
I'm a guest?
我是客人？
Just... I'm looking for the people responsible
只是…我在找相關的人
for-for-for Beckham,
認識貝克漢姆的
You are CIA, no?
你是中情局的？
I am very pleased to see CIA in my home.
有中情局的人來我家，我很高興
Please, sit.
請坐吧
How can I...
怎麼才能…
Be careful, the gun can go off.
當心，槍會走火！
USA friendly coming in.
我是美國軍人
Stop! Stop! Get the fuck down!
站住！跪下！
USA friendly,.
我是美國人！
On your knees, Get on your knees now.
跪下！快跪下
On your knees. You will be shot. Don't move.
跪下！否則就開槍了，不許動！
On your knees. Down now.
跪下！快
- Open your jacket!    - Opening my jacket,
- 掀開外套！    - 我掀了
Cover. Get him down,
把他摁在地上
- On the ground,    - I have a weapon
- 跪下    - 我有武器
Don't fucking move
不許動！
- Tower, hold cover. Searching.    - I have a weapon.
- 塔樓，掩護我，我來搜他    - 我有武器
- Gun.    - Like I said,.
- 有槍！    - 我早說過了
Weapons clear.
武器已收繳！
ID
身份證
What the fuck are you doing?
你他媽去幹嘛了？
I was at a whorehouse.
我去嫖妓了
All right, If I let you in, will you tell me where it is exactly?
好，我讓你進去，你告訴我妓院在哪裡
Yeah
好…
James, do you copy?
詹姆斯，你聽到了嗎？
James, do you have your ears on?
詹姆斯，你在聽嘛？
James?
詹姆斯？
This is James, What's up?
是我，怎麼了？
- Hey    - What's up, man?
- 嘿    - 怎麼了，夥計？
Look, we have a tank explosion in the Green Zone.
有個油罐在巴格達「綠區」爆炸了 （由美軍重點控制的安全區）
We have to post-blast assessment,
要我們去做爆後評估
see if it was a suicide bomber,
看看是不是自殺性爆炸
and if so, how the fuck did he do it?
如果是，再調查一下爆炸手法
Okay.
好
Where'd you say you were again?
你說你剛才去哪裡了？
I didn't, sergeant. Let's go.
我沒說過…我們走
What happened to your head, James?
你的頭怎麼了，詹姆斯？
Hey, you ready?
你準備好了嗎？
Game face, buddy. Let's go.
把護盔給我，老弟，要上路了
- You ready?    - Let's do this.
- 準備好了嗎？    - 好了
Rock and roll. Moving out.
好，我們上路了
USA friendlies coming through.
我們是美國友軍！
Make room, guys. Make room.
讓一讓，讓一讓！
Hey, Sanborn.
喂，桑伯恩
Oh, shit!
媽的
Get a medic! Get a medic!
叫醫生來！叫醫生來！
- An oil tanker?    - Yep,
- 是個油罐？    - 是的
That's a pretty long flight, huh?
飛了好長一段路啊
This is the edge of the blast radius.
爆炸一直蔓延到這裡
Jesus.
上帝啊
So, where's our triggerman?
襲擊者呢？
Burnt up in the flames, man.
已經燒沒了
Suicide bomber.
自殺式人肉炸彈
We're never going to find a body in that shit.
根本別想找到半點屍骨
What if there was no body?
如果不是肉體引爆
What if it was a remote det?
而是遙控引爆呢
A really good bad guy hides out in the dark, right?
有個大壞蛋就藏在暗處
Right here. Perfect vantage point,
就在那兒，地勢絕佳
outside the blast radius to sit back and watch us clean up their mess.
隔岸觀火，看著我們收拾殘局
- Want to go out there?    - Yes, I do
- 想過去嗎？    - 正想如此
- I could stand to get in a little trouble.    - No, man. This is bullshit.
- 這一去定會惹出些麻煩    - 不，夥計，你在胡搞
You got three infantry platoons behind you whose job it is to go Haji huntin'.
我們連有3個步兵排 他們的職責就是獵殺伊斯蘭佬
That ain't our fuckin' job.
這活不該我們干！
You don't say no to me, Sanborn. I say no to you.
你沒權駁我，桑伯恩，而我有權駁你
You know there are guys watching us right now.
你知道，那裡有群人正在看著我們
They're laughing at this, Okay, I'm not okay with that.
他們正在樂呢…對此我覺得很不爽
Now, turn off your god dammed torch 'cause we're going.
關了你的破手電筒，我們要過去了
Now we know where their oil tanker came from.
現在知道那油罐是從哪兒來的了
No shit. Same kind.
靠，同一型號的
- We're close    - Yeah
- 我們快到了    - 沒錯
The alley ways are probably set up on a grid.
這些小巷應該是縱橫交錯的
We're going to need to spit up, flush 'em out.
我們必須分路行動，把他們趕出來
Sanborn, you take one, Eldridge, take two,
桑伯恩你走第一條，艾綴奇走第二條
I got three. Rally point at your intersection.
我走第三條，在你的路口集合
- Ready, move    - Wait, rally point when?
- 好了，行動    - 等等，什麼時候集合？
Fuck
媽的
''Ipsura, ipsura,'' Go, go!
走開，走開！
Shit, Ahh.
該死！
Shit
媽的
- You got contact?    - Who was it? What's going on?
- 你遇敵了？    - 是誰？出了什麼事？
- What do you got?    - It's Eldridge.
- 什麼情況？    - 是艾綴奇
Go, go.
走， 走！
Man down! Man down!
人員傷亡，人員傷亡
Shit, Shit, Shit!
該死，該死!
- Negative, negative. It's not him.    - He's gone.
- 哦不不，不是他，不是他    - 他離開了
Where'd they go? Where'd they go?
他們去哪兒了？他們去哪兒了？
Tankers and troops are that way.
油罐車和大部隊在那邊
- Let's go this way.    - Fuck
- 我們這邊走    - 媽的
Use your torch, On three.
我數到三，你開手電
Ready?
準備好
One, two, three.
1…2…3
- Fuck!    - Shit
- 媽的    - 見鬼
Softy, softy, softy.
輕點，輕點，輕點
On three
我數到3
One, Two, Three
1…2…3…
Now! Go, go, go...
快過去！
- Eldridge, you okay?    - Fuck, dude, I'm hit.
- 艾綴奇，你還好嗎？    - 媽的，我受傷了
Hit him in the fuckin' leg.
他的腿被打傷了
Come on
撐住！撐住！
- Am I dead? Am I dead?    - No, You're fine, man.
- 我是不是快死了？    - 不，你沒事的，老弟
Am I dead? Am I dead?
我快死了，我快死了
I'm going to put some pressure down. Come on.
我要壓住它
You're all right.
你會沒事的
Look at me, look at me, You all right.
看著我，看著我！你會沒事的
All right, buddy. You ready to get up? On three, ready? One, two, three
好了，我數到3，你站起來 準備好，1…2…3…
Hey, what's up, man? What's up, man?
嘿，你好，夥計
Wanna buy some DVDs? Wanna play some soccer?
排爆男，要買DVD麼？ 想踢球麼？
What's up?
怎麼了？
Come on, man. Wanna play some...
來啊，夥計，來玩…
Aww, Fuck.
啊 媽的
How you doing, buddy?
你怎麼樣，老弟？
Doc says you're going to be okay.
醫生說你會沒事的
My fucking femur is shattered in nine places.
我的大腿骨斷成了9段
He said I'll be walking in six months if I'm fucking lucky.
要是在6個月後能走 我他媽就算走運了
- Six months ain't bad, huh?    - It's not bad?
- 6個月還好啊    - 還好？
Fuckin' sucks, man,
我靠你老母啊
- Ah, ah! Take it easy,
喂，輕點
You see that? You fuckin' see that?
看見沒？你看見沒？
That's what happens when you shoot someone, you motherfucker.
你想請別人吃槍子，結果就成了這樣
Sorry
對不起
- Sorry, Owen.    - Fuck you, Will.
- 對不起，歐文    - 去你媽的，威爾
Really, Fuck you.
就是這意思，去你媽的！
Thanks for saving my life, but we didn't have to go out.
謝謝你救了我的命 但我們不該去那裡找麻煩！
Looking for trouble to get your fucking adrenaline fix, you fuck.
就為了滿足你的個人衝動，你個混球！
Hey, take care of yourself, Owen.
好好照顧自己，歐文
Come home safe, man.
祝你平安歸來，夥計
- See you on the other side, man.    - All right
- 回家再見，夥計    - 好的
Let's get out of this fucking desert!
讓我們離開這該死的沙漠！
Don't move
別動！
If you keep walking we will shoot you.
如果你再往前走，我們只好開槍了！
Move him back
讓他退回去
Keep that translator back
把那翻譯拉回來！
- But the bomb was forced on him.    - Get him back!
- 那炸彈不是他自己裝在身上的    - 把他拉回來
Don't move! Stay still
站在原地別動！
If you keep walking we will shoot you. If you keep walking we will shoot.
如果你再往前走，我們只好開槍了！
Get that translator back, now!
快把那個翻譯拉回來！
Give him room, give him room.
讓一讓，讓一讓！
Hey, what do you got?
嘿，什麼情況？
He came walking up to our checkpoint,
他自己來到我們檢查站
said he had a bomb strapped to him, But he's sorry, doesn't want it to go off.
說自己身上綁著炸彈 但他不想讓炸彈爆炸
Then he starts begging us to take it off of him.
所以求我們拆除炸彈
Help this man, he's not a bad man.
幫幫他，他不是壞人！
He's not a bad man? He got a bomb strapped to him,
他不是壞人？他綁著炸彈！
This is a joke, he's trying to pull us closer.
他在逗我們，想讓我們靠近他
Yeah, I got it, I got it.
好了，我明白了
All right, look... Tell him to open his shirt slowly
好，告訴他，讓他慢慢地解開衣服
and see what's inside.
我要看看裡面是什麼
Slowly, slowly...
慢點，慢點
Jesus
啊，天哪！
All right Sergeant, I need a 75-meter perimeter.
好了中士，讓這些人離開75米遠
- Get these guys back.    - Give me 75 meters. Get back.
- 讓他們退後    - 離開75米，往後退！
You tell him to get on his knees and touch the sky, okay?
你告訴他，讓他跪下，手舉起來
Slowly
慢一些
Get down
跪下！
Okay, I need your radio.
好，我要用你的無線電
- Can't we just shoot him?    - No
- 能不能射殺了他？    - 不行
He's a family man. He's not a bad man.
他是個有家室的人，不是壞人
He's asking for help, only help.
他只想求助，求我們幫忙
Yeah, all right. You don't want to die, get back! I got it.
好了，如果你不想死，就退到後面去！ 我已經知道了
Listen, I know we've had our differences.
聽著，我知道我們有分歧
It happened, all right. It's water under the bridge.
這種事情總難免，但都已經過去了
This is suicide, man.
但你現在是去自殺，夥計
That's why they call it a suicide bomb, right?
所以才稱為自殺炸彈嘛
Let's do this. Come on.
我們來搞定它吧
He says the bomb may have a timer, please hurry.
他說炸彈上可能設置了定時器 請快點！
- We're good, Ready?    - Yep
- 我好了，你好了嗎？    - 好了
Go get 'em
去吧
- Let's do it    - See you
- 開始了    - 回見
- Watch the snipper huh!    - Yeah!
- 注意狙擊手    - 好的
Get your hands up
舉起手！
He says he has a family
他說他有家庭
Please help him,
請幫幫他
Now, listen
聽好了
Look, It'd be a lot easier for me to disarm this
如果我要拆炸彈，比較簡單的方法是
if I just shoot you. Do you understand?
先把你殺了，你明白嗎？
What's he saying?
他說什麼？
He says I don't wish to die, I have a family... Please take this off me.
他說他不想死，他還有家 請你把這東西從他身上拿下來
Tell him to put his hands behind his head or I'll be very happy to shoot him.
告訴他，把手放在頭後面 否則我很想開槍打他
Look, that's not what I said.
我不是這麼說的
Tell him to put his hands behind his head or I will shoot him.
告訴他，把手放在頭後面 否則就斃了他
Listen
聽著
Listen, listen.
聽著，聽著
You understand?
你聽明白了？
Okay
好
What do you got here?
看看有什麼？
He has four children.
他有四個孩子
Shit
見鬼
Sanborn, we got a timer, and we got a lot of wires, man.
桑伯恩，這有個計時器，還有很多線
I'm going to need a little help on this.
我需要幫助
Roger that, tell me what you need.
收到，告訴我，你要什麼？
Bolt cutters
我要鉗子
You gotta get down here in two minutes or we're all fucked.
最好在2分鐘內給我，不然就完了
Roger that, I'll be there in 30 seconds.
收到，30秒內給你
He says, please, I have a family.
他說求求你  我有個家庭
Sst
噓
I know, it's okay. You're all right. You're all right.
我知道，沒事的，你會好的，會好的
Please, don't leave me.
別離開我
You weren't fuckin' kidding.
你沒在開玩笑吧
Nope, What's this made out of?
沒有…這是什麼做的？
Oh, man
老天
This case's harder than steel
這玩意兒和鋼一樣硬
Shit
該死
- What's our time?    - We got two minutes    - Shit
- 還有多久？    - 還有2分鐘    - 媽的
We're going need a torch to get this off.
得用焊槍才行
Well, we don't have one of those in the fucking truck, man.
我們車裡可沒那玩意兒
He's dead, man.
他死定了，夥計
Hold on, man. Let me think. Just Let me think.
慢著，讓我想想，讓我想想
We're going to handle this. It's okay. We got this,
我們會搞定的，沒問題，想想…
Shh, okay.
噓，別吵
Now listen, you're gonna get back.
聽著，你先退開
It's just we don't got enough time, Sanborn.
我們時間不夠了，桑伯恩
I just gotta... I gotta get these bolts off.
我打算…我打算把這些鎖擰斷
No, We got a minute and a half, man. We gotta get out of here.
不，我們還有1分半鐘，必須離開這兒
- I'll handle this. Just go.    - Come on, man.
- 這裡我來處理，你快走    - 少來了，夥計
Look, I'm right behind ya. Just go.
我馬上就來，你先走吧
Fuck him! Come on, Let's go,
去他的，我們快走！
- Sanborn, I got the suit. Just go,    - James!
- 桑伯恩！我有防護衣，你快走！    - 詹姆斯！
Sanborn, you have 45 seconds. You have 45 seconds. Sanborn, Leave,
桑伯恩，還有45秒 你有45秒鐘，離開！
You're fucking dead, man. Dead.
你死定了，死定了
Go!
走！
- Everybody get back!    - Go, go!
- 所有人往後退！    - 走，走！
We got one.
拆掉了一個
Go, get back.
走，退後！
I can't. There's too many locks. There's too many, I can't do it,
不行，鎖太多了，太多了，我幹不了
I can't get it off. I'm sorry, Okay!
我沒法全弄掉，對不起了
You understand? I'm sorry,
明白嘛？我很抱歉，
I'm sorry. You hear me? I'm sorry,
對不起，對不起
- Get down now!    - I can help him.
- 快趴下    - 我去幫他
Everybody stay down!
大家趴下！
James!
詹姆斯！
Everybody up and out, James!
大家都起來，詹姆斯！
You all right?
你還好吧？
Aw, man,
哦，夥計
I fuckin' hate this place.
我真他媽討厭這鬼地方
Here, man. Have a hit.
給你，喝一口
I'm not ready to die, James.
我還沒準備死呢，詹姆斯
Well, you're not going to die out here, bro.
你不會死在這裡的，兄弟
Another two inches.
就差2英吋
Shrapnel zings by, slices my throat.
彈片呼嘯而過，然後把我的喉嚨割破
I bleed out like a pig in the sand,
我會像頭豬一樣，在沙漠裡流血不止
Nobody'll give a shit.
沒有人會在乎我
I mean, my parents'll care, but they don't count, man, Who else?
我父母當然會在意，但他們不能算 老兄，還會有誰在意呢？
I don't even have a son.
我連兒子都沒有
Well, you're going to have plenty of time for that, amigo.
想生兒子，你有的是時間，朋友
- Naw, man    - You know?
- 不，夥計    - 這你知道
I'm done,
我不想幹了
I want a son,
我想要個兒子
I want a little boy, Will.
我想要個小男孩，威爾
I mean, how do you do it, you know?
我想知道，你是怎麼做的
Take the risk?
去冒那樣的風險？
I don't know, I just...
我不知道，我只是…
I guess I don't think about it.
我只是從來不去想
But you realize every time you suit up,
但是當你每次穿上拆彈服
every time we go out
每次我們出勤
it's life or death. You roll the dice
就會面對死亡 你賭上自己的命
and you deal with it.
去處理這些事情
You recognize that, don't you?
這些你都清楚，是不是？
Yeah
是的
Yeah, I do.
是這樣沒錯
But I don't know why.
但我不知道為什麼
Yeah.
對
I don't know, JT. You know why I am the way I am?
我不知道…知道我為什麼會這樣？
Naw, I don't.
我不知道
- Wow! You did some shopping.    - Yeah.
- 哇，你買了不少東西！    - 是啊
I got some soda. We done?
我買了些蘇打水，可以去結賬了麼？
You want to go get us some cereal and I'll meet you at the checkout?
幫我們拿些麥片來，在收銀台會合？
Okay, cereal.
好吧，麥片
Where?
在哪兒…？
Some guy drove his truck to the middle of an Iraqi market,
有人把貨車開到伊拉克一個集市中央
starts passing out free candies.
開始發放免費糖果
All the kids coming running up, the families stuff,
所有孩子都跑過去，還有孩子的家人
He detonates.
那人引爆了炸彈
They're saying 59 are dead.
據報道有59人死亡
You know they need more bomb techs.
他們需要補充拆彈員，這你知道
You want to chop those up for me?
幫我把這些切碎
Yeah
對了
You love playing with that.
你喜歡玩這個啊
You love playing with all your stuffed animals.
你喜歡玩毛絨玩具
You love your mommy, your daddy, your nature pajamas.
你喜歡媽媽，喜歡爸爸 喜歡你的小睡衣
You love everything, don't you? Yeah
你什麼都喜歡，是不是？
You know what, buddy?
知道嗎？
Once you get older,
等你長大了
some of the things that you love might not seem so special anymore.
曾經喜歡的東西也許會變得不再特別
Like your Jack In The Box,
就像這個玩偶盒
Maybe you realize it's just a piece of tin and a stuffed animal
你會發現那只是一片鐵皮加一個人偶
and then you forget the few things you really love,
那些原本鍾愛的東西會漸漸被你遺忘
And by the time you get to my age maybe it's only one or two things,
到了我這個年紀，鍾愛的東西 也許只剩下一兩件了
With me I think it's one,
對我來說只剩一件了
- Welcome to Delta Company    - Sergeant
- 歡迎來到D連    - 中士